JONATHAN CAREY SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Bloomington, IN 812-821-6304 jonathan.carey13@yahoo.com Linkedin Portfolio Github

Career Goal

I am a computer software developer and multimedia professional. I recently completed an immersive software development course at Eleven Fifty Academy, and have been continuing to learn new development skills and languages on my own. Previously, I was self-employed for 3 years as a production design contractor in the film and advertising industry. I am an experienced collaborator, with a strong work ethic and a love of problem-solving. I am currently seeking a full-time position in software development or a related field.

Skills

Software Development: C#, ASP.NET, Xamarin, Model View Controller (MVC), Unit Testing

Database: SQL, relational databases

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API development, HTTP methods, responsive web design **Other:** Unity, Agile/Scrum methodology, pair programming, GitHub, reading/writing documentation

Education

Eleven Fifty Academy: Software Development

August 2020 - February 2021

- Immersed in a 24-week intensive program with curriculum based on current industry demands
- Acquired 500+ hours of coding time using the .NET framework and related applications
- Designed and built individual and team projects following Agile/Scrum methodology
- Engaged in workshops with a range of professionals in the tech industry

Indiana University: Bachelor of Arts in Telecommunication Design and Production

August 2013 - May 2017

- Developed skills to create film, television, digital, screen and aural media at one of the top-ranked programs internationally
- Completed degree in 4 years while working continuously at multiple jobs

Sample Software Design Projects

A Home Inventory API: See the Code

• Team project using JavaScript and C# to create a program that can store household items for documentation Video Game Management Web App: See the Code / See the Project

- Designed and developed a web application built upon N-Tier architecture and MVC for users to catalogue their personal library of games and track related updates
- Wrote detailed documentation describing how to use and modify this application

Professional Experience

Production Design Contractor: Self-Employed, Greater Indianapolis Area, IN

August 2017 - May 2020

- Contracted by companies in the highly competitive multimedia production field
- Collaborated with creative teams and departments to achieve the vision of the clients
- Created and deconstructed custom scene structures and props used for film productions
- Utilized problem-solving and interpersonal skills to overcome design challenges and team conflicts

Film Archivist: Memnon Archiving Services, Bloomington, IN

October 2019 – Present

- Repair, clean, digitalize, and perform color grading and corrections for physical film for clients
- Trained to calibrate and operate specialized LaserGraphics ScanStation machines

Jobs during college included 3 years with Facility Operations and Services at IU and 3 years at Denny's restaurant